So we're now going to run a large language model directly on your box using a platform called llama,
이제 여러분 컴퓨터에 직접적으로 큰 언어 모델을 실행하겠습니다 llama라는 플랫폼을
which lets you run C plus plus code version of Llms compiled directly on your machine.
사용해서요 여러분 컴퓨터에서 직접 컴파일된 C++ 코드 버전의 Lms를 실행할 수 있도록요
I'm going to start by showing you on windows, and then we'll flip over to Mac.
먼저 윈도우부터 보여드리고 맥으로 넘어갈게요
So to start with llama you bring up your favorite browser.
라마를 시작으로 좋아하는 브라우저를 불러오세요
Let's go to Microsoft Edge.
마이크로소프트 Edge로 가죠
And you can simply go to llama.
라마로 가면 돼요
Com or just search llama llama it's O followed by llama.
라마 라마를 검색하면 O 다음에 라마가 나와요
And the first hit here in the search results will be Alarm.com.
검색 결과의 첫 번째 타자는 Alam이에요 코무요
And here it is.
여기 있네요
It's called llama because it was initially built around a model that's called llama, which is the open
llama라고 불리는 이유는 처음에 llama라는 모델 주위에 만들어졌기
source model from meta, which really stole the show a couple of years ago when it first came out.
때문이죠 메타의 오픈 소스 모델로 몇 년 전 처음 나왔을 때 정말 인기를 끌었죠
So downloading is as simple as pressing the download button.
다운로드 작업은 다운로드 버튼을 누르는 것만큼 간단해요
And once you press the download button, you press download for windows and it will start to download
다운로드 버튼을 누르면 윈도우용 다운로드가 시작되고 윈도우 버전을
the windows version.
다운로드하게 되죠
And if I look here at my downloads, I will see that it has downloaded.
제가 다운로드한 것을 보면 다운로드 된 것을 볼 수 있어요.
There's a Setup.exe.
함정이에요 exe요
If I press the open file button, it will prompt me.
파일 열기 버튼을 누르면 프롬프트가 뜨죠
Oh, it's still.
아직 안 움직이네요
It's still downloading again.
아직도 다운로드 중이에요
I just ran this.
방금 이걸 실행했어요
It will prompt me to install it locally, which I will do as soon as it's installed locally.
로컬에 설치하라고 할 텐데 로컬에 설치되자마자 할 거예요
You then go to the start menu and you're probably familiar with this, but you bring up a PowerShell
시작 메뉴로 가면 아마 익숙하실 텐데 PowerShell을 불러오죠
by typing power in here, and as soon as you do, it prompts you and you press open and up comes a PowerShell,
여기 PowerShell을 입력하면 프롬프트 되고 열기를 누르면 PowerShell이
which is where we are going right now to run a large language model.
나와요 지금 큰 언어 모델을 실행할 곳이죠
Minutes into this course and the way we do it is we simply type once.
몇 분 후 수업이 시작됐는데 그냥 한 번만 입력하면 돼요
Once that install is completed and you pressed okay, you can just simply say olama o l l a m a run.
설치가 완료되고 확인을 누르면 그냥 ohama o l l a m a run이라고 하면 돼요
And now you put the name of the model next, and the name of the model we're going to use is going to
모델의 이름을 다음이라고 입력합니다. 우리가 사용할 모델의 이름은
be llama 3.2, which is one of the very newest models.
llama 3이 될 거예요. 2는 최신 모델 중 하나죠
And so here it goes.
자, 시작할게요
And it's run.
달려요
It's happening right now.
지금 진행 중이에요
That blinking cursor means that we have a large language model running on this computer.
저 깜빡이는 커서가 의미하는 건 이 컴퓨터에서 큰 언어 모델이 실행된다는 거죠
It might take a bit longer for you the first time.
비트는 처음보다 시간이 더 걸릴 거예요
It has to download the 2 billion parameters associated with Lama, and depending on your internet connection,
이것은 Lama와 관련된 20억 개의 파라미터를 다운로드 해야 합니다. 당신의 인터넷 연결에 따라 시간이 좀 걸릴 수도
that might take a little bit, but you'll get a progress bar that will show you what's going on.
있지만 진행률 표시줄이 어떤 일이 일어나는지 보여줄 거예요. Get it.
So what we're now going to do is try and talk to this LLM, and we're going to try and do something
이제 이 LLM과 얘길 해보겠습니다 free LLM으로 뭔가
useful with a free LLM.
유용한 걸 해보려고요
And here's what we'll do.
이렇게 하죠
I'm actually trying to learn Spanish at the moment.
지금은 스페인어를 배우려고 해요
And I can tell you that my grasp of the Spanish language is distinctly less inferior to my grasp of
그리고 제 스페인어 실력은 확실히 less llms에 비하면 한참
llms.
아래죠
And the app that I'm using to try and teach me has a service where you can pay to chat with a with an
제가 사용하고 있는 앱에 AI 튜터와 채팅하려면 돈을 내야 하는 서비스가
AI tutor.
있어요
Now, I don't want to pay for that because I know I can run an open source model and do it for free.
돈을 내고 싶진 않아요 오픈 소스 모델을 무료로 실행할 수 있으니까요
So right now we're going to build ourselves a Spanish tutor which will teach me Spanish.
스페인어 선생님을 만들 거예요 저를 가르쳐 주실 분요
All open source without paying a penny.
전부 오픈 소스예요
So I'm going to say I am trying to learn Spanish.
스페인어를 배우려고 한다고 할게요
I am a complete beginner.
전 완전히 초보예요
Please chat with me in basic Spanish to teach me.
기초 스페인어로 대화 좀 해 주세요
And so that is the prompt that we will start with.
이 프롬프트에서 시작할 거예요
And let's see what happens.
어떻게 되는지 보죠
It's thinking.
생각 중이에요
Hola.
안녕하세요
Welcome to our conversation in Spanish.
스페인어 대화에 오신 걸 환영해요
To start, let's begin with some basic greetings.
기본적인 인사말부터 시작해 보죠
Como estas?
안녕하세요?
So you can see that it's giving me a very good starting prompt.
아주 좋은 시작 프롬프트를 제공하고 있는 걸 보실 수 있죠
It's giving me some examples.
예를 들어볼게요
It understands where I'm coming from.
제 입장을 이해해주죠
And I can now say something like.
지금은 이런 말도 할 수 있어요
Put an accent on.
Put it, Put it, Put it 악센트를 넣어 주세요
Uh, so.
네
Oh, there's a small mistake.
작은 실수가 있어요
Okay, there we go.
좋아요, 됐어요
It's correcting me.
정정하고 있어요
I think it's the accent that I missed and maybe the question mark as well, so you get the idea.
억양을 놓친 것 같아요 물음표도요 어떤 건지 아시겠죠? Get it
We've actually just built something which has commercial value because indeed, this is sold at a price
상업적 가치가 있는 걸 방금 만들었어요 왜냐하면 우리 박스에서 즉시
immediately for free on our boxes using an open source LLM that is llms in action from the get go.
무료로 팔리거든요 오픈 소스 LLM을 이용해서요 get go부터 작동하는 llms죠
And now for Mac people, let's flip over to a mac.
이제 Mac으로 넘어가죠 Mac으로 넘어가죠